<Document>
  # Consent
  This guidebook entry will cover setting up Consent Settings as well as reading others' Consent Settings.

  ## How To Set Up
  Near the top-right of your screen should be a gear icon, this button opens up the Consent Settings editor.
  You have two tabs to edit, "Character Specific" which is tied to your current character, or "Account Specific" which shows up for all characters.
  The third tabs shows a preview of what it might look like when finished.

  This allows certain formatting options such as:

  <Box> extlink="Display Text" link="https://example.com/"</Box>
  Using this format, you can add a link to an outside custom character page.

  You can also use nearly any settings that work for standard paperwork, such as color and header changes.

  Consent options can be used to showcase NSFW limits or interests for a potential RP scenario, as well as outline how you would prefer to be interacted with during an RP scenario.

 ## Consent Toggles

  Below the text field for your account-specific consent options exists several toggles to allow or disallow certain interactions, be it admin memes or other extreme/taboo mechanics such as vore and aphrodesiacs.


  ## How To View Others Consent
  Inspecting any character with shift-click should provide a symbol next to the ones you would regularly expect, it looks like a human head with gears inside. Click this to view another players consent settings.

 ## Subtle LOOC
  Before engaging in any adult scenarios with other players, please make sure you are being respectful to any of their possible outlined consent preferences. If you are unsure of how they might feel or otherwise don't provide enough information in their settings menu, be sure to use [color=pink]Subtle LOOC[/color] (prefix "=") to confirm how they would feel about it.

  If you do engage in any roleplay scenes that contain extreme content, please be sure to use Subtle messages. These are essentially the same as an emote, however only reach players who are in whisper distance. These subtle messages also cannot be seen by ghosts. The prefix for Subtle is -.

  ## Ship OOC
  If you are in a situation where you need to use LOOC to communicate with someone on another ship, such as during ship-to-ship combat, you can use [color=PaleGoldenRod]Ship OOC[/color] (prefix &) to communicate at ranges that LOOC may not reach. This OOC chat has a range of approximately 750m in-game and will show which vessel you are speaking from.
</Document>
